Emile Berliner Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 13. Recordings, circa 1890-1950s, Over 400 sound discs, including zinc, copper, celluloid, rubber, shellac, and vinyl pressings and masters, in various speeds, and in sizes ranging from 5 to 12 inches in diameter
  - Just as the sun went down Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., Udall, Lyn.; 1 sound disc: analog, 69 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0323 (Disc Berliner 0323)
    Recorded at an unknown location, July 11, 1899.
  - Laughing song Published: Philadelphia, Pa.: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1896., Jones, Sidney, 1861-1946.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 8 1/2 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1302 Y (Disc Berliner 1302 Y)
    Maurice Farkoa, tenor; piano acc.
    Recorded in Philadelphia, Pa., May 8, 1896.
  - Lincoln's speech at Gettysburg Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone. 1898., Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865.; 1 sound disc: analog, 72.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 6012 (Disc Berliner 6012)
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., Sept. 21, 1898.
  - Los lindos ojos Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1233 (Disc Berliner 1233)
    Eugenie M. Ferrer, soprano; piano acc.
    Autograph of Ferrer inscribed in zinc master.
  - The little speranza Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., 1 sound disc: analog, 66.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0607 (Disc Berliner 0607)
    Recorded at an unknown location, Oct. 13, 1899.
  - The Lord is my shepherd Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [190-], 1 sound disc: analog, 69 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0895 (Disc Berliner 0895)
    Harry Macdonough, tenor; Florence Hayward, soprano; piano acc.
  - Malin Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 2979 (Disc NCPB 1104)
  - The man behind the gun Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1900., 1 sound disc: analog, 71 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0928 (Disc Berliner 0928)
    Recorded at an unknown location, Feb. 27, 1900.
  - Manhattan Beach march Published: Washington, D.C.: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1897., Sousa, John Philip, 1854-1932.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 149 Y (Disc Berliner 149 Y)
    Performed by an unidentified military band.
    Recorded in Washington, D.C., Apr. 24, 1897.
  - Medley quadrille: with figures called. Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [190-], 1 sound disc: analog, 68.8 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0913 (Disc Berliner 0913)
    Performed by the Metropolitan Orchestra.
  - Morning on the farm Published: Washington, D.C.: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1897., Wood, N. R.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 401 Y (Disc Berliner 401 Y)
    N.R. Wood, vocals.
    Recorded in Washington, D.C., Aug. 5, 1897.
  - Morning on the farm Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1896., Wood, N. R.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 401 X (Disc Berliner 401 X)
    Recorded at an unknown location, Feb. 15, 1896.
  - Morning on the farm Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Wood, N. R.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 401 (Disc Berliner 401)
    Recorded at an unknown location, Nov. 1898.
    Autograph of Wood inscribed in zinc master.
  - Musin mazurka Published: New York: Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., 1 sound disc: analog, 66.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; Berliner's Gramophone 4800 (Disc Berliner 4800)
    Jennie Hoyle, violin; piano acc.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., July 26, 1898.
    Autograph of Jennie Hoyle inscribed in zinc master.
  - My old Kentucky home Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1897., Foster, Stephen Collins, 1826-1864.; 1 sound disc: analog, 61.1 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 175 YY (Disc Berliner 175 YY)
    Edward M. Favor, tenor; piano acc.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., June 30, 1897.
  - My sins rose as high as a mountain Published: Washington, D.C.: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 2000 (Disc NCPB 1098)
  - National fantasie Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], 1 sound disc: analog, 62.1 rpm, mono.; 8 1/2 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 233 Y (Disc Berliner 233 Y)
    William Paris Chambers, cornet; piano acc.
    Autograph of Chambers inscribed in zinc master.
  - Zenda waltzes Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Witmark, Frank M.; 1 sound disc: analog, 66 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 7002 Z (Disc Berliner 7002 Z)
    Performed by Higgins' Orchestra; Henry Higgins, conductor.
    Autograph of Higgins (conductor) inscribed in zinc master.
  - Never did the same thing twice Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., McGlennon, Felix, 1856-1943.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 75.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1731 Z (Disc Berliner 1731 Z)
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., Mar. 31, 1898.
    Autograph of Quinn inscribed in zinc master.
  - Ocean breezes Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924.; 1 sound disc: analog, 67.6 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 8018 Z (Disc Berliner 8018 Z)
    Victor Herbert's 22nd Regiment Band; Otto Schneiber, conductor.
    Autograph of Otto Schneiber inscribed in zinc master.
  - Old folks at home Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Foster, Stephen Collins, 1826-1864.; 1 sound disc: analog, 62.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 301 Z (Disc Berliner 301 Z)
    August P. Stengler, clarinet; piano acc.
  - On hope Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1897., Ingersoll, Robert Green, 1833-1899.; 1 sound disc: analog, 77 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 697 (Disc Berliner 697)
    Robert G. Ingersoll, speaker.
    Recorded in New York, Dec. 31, 1897.
    Autograph of Ingersoll inscribed in zinc master.
  - On the banks of the Wabash Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Dresser, Paul, 1858-1906.; 1 sound disc: analog, 63 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 3428 (Disc Berliner 3428)
    Arthur Pryor, trombone; Henry Higgins, cornet.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., Mar. 28, 1899.
    Autographs of Pryor and Higgins inscribed in zinc master.
  - Orange blossoms Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1897., Pryor, Arthur, 1870-1942.; 1 sound disc: analog, 64.1 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 65 (Disc Berliner 65)
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., Aug. 18, 1898.
  - Original schottische Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1897., 1 sound disc: analog, 62.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 334 (Disc Berliner 334)
    Joseph Norrito, clarinet; piano acc.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., Aug. 3, 1897.
  - The palms Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., Faure, J. (Jean), 1830-1914.; 1 sound disc: analog, 70 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0297 (Disc Berliner 0297)
    F. Giannini, tenor; piano acc.
    Recorded at an unknown location, June 28, 1899.
    Autograph of Giannini inscribed in zinc master.
  - Polka variata Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., 1 sound disc: analog, 66 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0598 (Disc Berliner 0598)
    Jean B.H. Moeremans, saxophone; Jacques L. van Poucke, clarinet; piano acc.
    Autographs of Moeremans and Poucke inscribed in zinc master.
  - Pomona waltz Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1897., Waldteufel, Emil, 1837-1915.; 1 sound disc: analog, 62.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1466 Z (Disc Berliner 1466 Z)
    Performed by an unidentified orchestra.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., July 1, 1897.
  - Pretty little dark blue eyes Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1897., 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 3251 Z (Disc Berliner 3251 Z)
    Charles P. Lowe, xylophone; piano acc.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., Oct. 12, 1897.
  - Private Tommy Atkins Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., 1 sound disc: analog, 69.7 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 159 ZZ (Disc Berliner 159 ZZ)
    John Terrell, baritone; piano acc.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Oct. 20, 1898.
  - Rendez vous valse Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], 1 sound disc: analog, 69.8 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1464 Z (Disc Berliner 1464 Z)
  - Rock of ages Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Hastings, Thomas, 1784-1872.; 1 sound disc: analog, 67 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 917 X (Disc Berliner 917 X)
    Albert C. Campbell, tenor; piano accompaniment.
    Autograph of Campbell inscribed in zinc master.
  - Santa Lucia Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., 1 sound disc: analog, 69.8 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1617 W (Disc Berliner 1617 W)
    Ferruccio Giannini, tenor; with piano.
  - Scarlet letter Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Gaisberg, Frederick William.; 1 sound disc: analog, 74.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 490 (Disc Berliner 490)
    Recorded at an unknown location, Apr. 1898.
  - Sentiments on the Cuban question Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Buffalo Bill, 1846-1917.; 1 sound disc: analog, 69 rpm, mono.; 8 1/2 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 5014 (Disc NCPB 1126)
    William F. Cody (Buffalo Bill), speaker.
    Recorded in New York, N,Y., Apr. 20, 1898.
    Autograph signature (as William F. Cody) inscribed in zinc master of Berliner disc.
  - The seraph Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Chambers, William Paris, 1854-1913.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 8 1/2 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 235 ZZ (Disc NCPB 1123)
  - The serenade Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1897., Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924.; 1 sound disc: analog, 69 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 471 (Disc Berliner 471)
    Vess L. Ossman, banjo; piano acc.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Oct. 9, 1897.
  - The shadows on the door Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., 1 sound disc: analog, 62 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0123 (Disc Berliner 0123)
    Will F. Denny, tenor; piano acc.
    Recorded at an unknown location, May 2, 1899.
    Autograph of Denny inscribed in zinc master.
  - A son of the desert am I Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Phillips, Walter A.; 1 sound disc: analog, 63 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1808 (Disc Berliner 1808)
    J. W. Myers, baritone; piano acc.
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., Mar. 26, 1898.
    Autograph of Myers inscribed in zinc master.
  - Sonambula aria Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Bellini, Vincenzo, 1801-1835.; 1 sound disc: analog, 70.3, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1114 (Disc Berliner 1114)
  - Sounds from the sunny South Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., 1 sound disc: analog, 62.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1483 (Disc Berliner 1483)
    Performed by Metropolitan Orchestra.
  - Spaghetti polka Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., 1 sound disc: analog, 69.3 rpm, mono.; 8 1/2 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 345 (Disc NCPB 1087)
    F. Jardella, clarinet; piano acc.
  - Stars and stripes forever march Published: Washington, D.C.: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1897., Sousa, John Philip, 1854-1932.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 65.6 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 61 Y (Disc Berliner 61 Y)
    Unidentified military band.
    Recorded in Washington, D.C., May 27, 1897.
  - The stars and stripes forever Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Sousa, John Philip, 1854-1932.; 1 sound disc: analog, 68 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 470 Z (Disc Berliner 470 Z)
  - Street fakir Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1896., Graham, George, fl. 1896-1903.; 1 sound disc: analog, 69 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 638 Y (Disc Berliner 638 Y)
    George Graham, speaker.
    Recorded at an unknown location, May 23, 1896.
  - Street piano Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., 1 sound disc: analog, 62.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0836 (Disc Berliner 0836)
    Unidentified barrel organist.
    Recorded at an unknown location, Dec. 19, 1899.
  - Sweet, sweet love Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1899., Bowers, Frederic V., 1874-1961.; 1 sound disc: analog, 65.1 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0264 (Disc Berliner 0264)
    Arthur Pryor, trombone; piano acc.
    Autograph of Pryor inscribed in zinc master.
  - Sweetest story ever told Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Stults, R. M.; 1 sound disc: analog, 67.5 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 893 Y (Disc Berliner 893 Y)
    Autograph of S.H. Dudley (baritone and mangager) inscribed in zinc master.
  - The sword of Bunker Hill Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1894., Covert, B. (Bernard), b. 1820.; 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 902 (Disc Berliner 902)
    Samuel Ross, baritone; piano acc.
    recorded at an unknown location, Nov. 20, 1894.
  - Talk on money Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1896., Graham, George, fl. 1896-1903.; 1 sound disc: analog, 67 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 645 Z (Disc Berliner 645 Z)
    Recorded at an unknown location, June 2, 1896.
  - Tramp, tramp, tramp Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Root, George F. (George Frederick), 1820-1895.; 1 sound disc: analog, 65 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 157 Y (Disc Berliner 157 Y)
    Recorded in New York, N.Y., June 10, 1898.
  - Uncle Josh Weathersby in a department store Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone. 1898., Stewart, Cal, 1856-1919.; 1 sound disc: analog, 62.6 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 6007 (Disc Berliner 6007)
    Cal Stewart, speaker.
    Autograph of Stewart inscribed in zinc master.
  - Vive la Canadienne Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1316 (Disc Berliner 1316)
    Eugene Danton, baritone; piano acc.
    Autograph of Danton inscribed in zinc master.
  - When Johny [sic] comes marching home Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., Gilmore, P. S. (Patrick Sarsfield), 1829-1892.; 1 sound disc: analog, 64.2 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 177 YY (Disc Berliner 177 YY)
    John Terrell, baritone; piano accompaniment.
  - Where is my wandering boy tonight? Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Lowry, Robert, 1826-1899.; 1 sound disc: analog, 69.8 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 0382 (Disc Berliner 0382)
  - Whistling medley Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1898., 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm. mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 427 (Disc Berliner 427)
    Milton M. Clark, whistler.
  - William Tell overture Published: New York: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868.; 1 sound disc: analog, 60 rpm, mono.; 8 1/2 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 7 X (Disc NCPB 1042)
    Performed by Banda Rossa (musical group).
  - Zizzy, ze zum zum Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, [189-], Udall, Lyn.; 1 sound disc: analog, 66.4 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 1923 Z (Disc Berliner 1923 Z)
  - Zyczenie: Polish song no. 6. Published: [United States]: E. Berliner's Gramophone, 1900., 1 sound disc: analog, between 66 and 72 rpm, mono.; 7 in.; E. Berliner's Gramophone 01047 (Disc Berliner 01047)
- Series 14. Scrapbooks, 1885-1930, 5.5 linear feet
  Series 14 consists of twelve scrapbooks that contain newspaper clippings, letters, articles, pamphlets, and advertisements. Topics documented in the scrapbooks include Berliner’s inventions -- particularly the phonograph, acoustic tile, and microphone improvements -- as well as issues of importance to him, such as Palestine, Zionism, and milk pasteurization. One scrapbook contains jokes, poetry, and health poems Berliner wrote for newspaper publications.
  - 1926-1928 (Box 18)
    Includes clippings and letters referring to a Berliner biography written by William Wile, Berliner’s proof on microphonic air-gap theory, and public health work.
  - 1917-1928 (Box 19)
    Articles on the phonograph, gramophone, microphone, and telephone. Also poetry, jokes, and health poems.
  - Acoustic tiles, 1930 (Box 20)
    Letters of recommendation, articles, and ads on the Berliner acoustic tile system.
  - 1926-1928 (Box 21)
    Articles and letters on public health work and on the invention of the microphone and acoustic tiles, as well as a biography by William Wile.
  - Partially filled scrapbook, 1885-1894 (Box 22)
    Empty except for three pages relating to the U.S. Gramophone Co. Included are invitations to stockholders’ meetings, gramophone drawings, and an article on cloud telegraphy.
  - Palestine and Zionism [“p & z”], 1918-1919 (Box 23)
    Articles, pamphlets, and letters on Palestine and Zionism.
  - Milk pasteurization and health [“m & h”], 1917-1925 (Box 24)
    Letters, pamphlets, and clippings related to milk pasteurization and health issues.
  - Lawsuit letters and records, 1877-1878 (Box 25)
    Letters concerning Berliner’s testimony in telephone transmitter lawsuits.
  - Milk, 1910 (Box 26)
    Letters and clippings on the health risks of drinking unpasteurized milk.
  - Acoustics, 1925-1928 (Box 27)
    Handwritten notes, letters, pamphlets, and photographs relating to acoustic tiles. Includes a patent for acoustic tiles.
  - Berliner-Edison controversy, 1928 (Box 28)
    Articles and letters on the Edison congressional medal controversy.
  - Historical accounts of the invention of the telephone, phonograph, graphophone, and gramophone (Box OS 3-OS 4)
    Two scrapbooks containing pamphlets, brochures, clippings, letters, and photographs.
- Series 15. Joseph Sanders materials, 1896-1927, 1953-1955, 2 linear feet
  The Joseph Sanders materials were donated to the Library of Congress by his son, Robert Sanders.
  Joseph Sanders, a nephew of Emile Berliner, was for many years Berliner’s laboratory assistant, concentrating on matrix making and the development of record materials. The Joseph Sanders material includes patents, correspondence, booklets, tax forms, brochures and newspaper clippings, telephonic equipment, gramophones, laboratory apparatus, and acoustic paneling. Diaries from the Sanders donation are housed in series 7, Journals and Diaries, and sound recordings are documented in series 13, Recordings.
  - Emile Berliner tax forms, 1917-1927 (Box-folder 31/1-2)
  - Joseph Sanders fax forms, 1917-1927 (Box-folder 31/3)
  - Cora Berliner tax forms, 1917-1927 (Box-folder 31/4)
  - Telephon-Fabrik catalog, J. Berliner, 1896-1897 (Box-folder 31/5)
  - Patent booklets on copyright infringement cases involving Joseph Sanders, 1919-1910 (Box-folder 31/6)
  - Patent booklets on copyright infringement cases involving Joseph Sanders and Louise Berliner, 1905, 1909 (Box-folder 31/7)
  - Multiplexgrammophon patents, 1905-1910 (Box-folder 32/8)
  - European patents, 1904-1913 (Box-folder 32/9)
  - Austria no. 24624, gramophone record patents (Box-folder 32/10)
  - Floor covering patents, 1902 (Box-folder 32/11-12)
  - Composition of matter patents, 1903-1905 (Box-folder 32/13)
  - Gramophone patents, 1904-1907 (Box-folder 32/14)
  - Patents for gramophone record tablets, 1904-1905 (Box-folder 32/15)
  - Arguments submitted to German patent office overcoming opposition to S.19988 and S. 20853, 1906-1911 (Box-folder 32/16)
  - Gramophone improvement patents, 1904-1906 (Box-folder 32/17)
    Relates to the yoke supported neck.
  - Patents and correspondence relating to improvement in sound, 1908-1916 (Box-folder 33/18)
  - Sound record tablet patent applications #204, #024, 1904-1910 (Box-folder 33/19)
  - German patent S. 20855, Improvement in sound record tablets, 1905-1912 (Box-folder 33/20-22)
  - J. Sanders patents, 1905-1916 (Box-folder 33/23)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1904, 1910, 1915, undated (Box-folder 33/24)
  - Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box-folder 33/25A-B)
  - Interference #24,849, Sanders v. Schumacher, sound record tablet, 1905 (Box-folder 34/26)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 34/27)
    Original folder was marked “G.”
  - Correspondence between Joseph Sanders and B.L. Aldridge, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 34/28)
  - Interference #27784, A. Smith and Wicks v. Emerson v. Sanders, gramophone record tablet, 1904-1911 (Box-folder 34/29)
  - Correspondence relating to J. Sanders v. Edgar, 1908-1909 (Box-folder 34/30)
  - Correspondence of Lyons & Bissing, attorneys, 1903-1908 (Box-folder 34/31)
  - Correspondence relating to Austria and Russia, A1344-05/A161909, Improvements in sound record tablets/paper coated facing (Box-folder 34/32)
- Series 16. Acoustic Tile, 1899, 1925-1929, 2.5 linear feet
  No online presentation of the items in Series 16 is available.
  This series contains correspondence and other materials regarding Berliner’s invention of acoustic tile.
  The series is arranged in alphabetical order with unidentified letters filed at the end. Folders of news clippings from 1927 regarding the invention follow the correspondence.
  - Correspondence
    - American Piano Supply Co., 1926 (Box-folder 35/1)
    - American Wire Fabrics Corp., 1926-1928 (Box-folder 35/2)
    - Miscellaneous A, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 35/3)
    - Ballou, Frank M., 1927, 1929 (Box-folder 35/4)
    - Bates Valve Bag Co., 1927-1928 (Box-folder 35/5)
    - Bell Telephone Laboratories, 1925, 1927 (Box-folder 35/6)
    - Berliner, Joseph, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 35/7)
    - Berry, F. E., Jr., 1925, 1927 (Box-folder 35/8)
    - Miscellaneous B, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 35/9)
    - Casein Manufacturing Group, 1926, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 35/10)
    - Cohn, Milton, 1928 (Box-folder 35/11)
    - Commissioners of the District of Columbia, 1925, 1927 (Box-folder 35/12)
    - Miscellaneous C, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 35/13)
    - Miscellaneous D, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 35/14)
    - Miscellaneous E, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 35/15)
    - F.S. & G.L. Brown Machine Co., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 36/1)
    - Miscellaneous F, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 36/2)
    - Commissioners of the District of Columbia, 1927 (Box-folder 36/3)
    - Miscellaneous G, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 36/4)
    - Heilprin, W. A., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 36/5-7)
    - Miscellaneous H, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 36/8)
    - Miscellaneous I, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 36/9)
    - John R. Livezey Co., 1927-1928 (Box-folder 36/10)
    - Journal of the American Institute of Architects, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 36/11)
    - Miscellaneous J, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 36/12)
    - Miscellaneous K, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 37/1)
    - Ludlow, Israel, 1926 (Box-folder 37/2)
    - Miscellaneous L, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 37/3)
    - Methodist Episcopal Church South, 1926, 1928 (Box-folder 37/4)
    - Miscellaneous M, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 37/5)
    - National Association for Music in Hospitals, Inc., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 37/6)